WALI MOHAMED

 fr:
 London, UK

 ☎:
 07737889846

 ☒:
 walimah@gmail.com

 Portfolio:
 www.wali.ara.uk

I am a trained and established Mathematics Teacher with over ten years of experience. I decided to change my career to IT due to my previous aspirations in programming. I studied Data Science, and Machine Learning at WQU and Udemy last year which further ignited my passion for IT. I have completed the Software Development Bootcamp at JUST IT Training where I gained further knowledge to improve my skills and grasp a better understanding of software languages such as (HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, and Python). I'm also working on my portfolio to create more personal projects. Looking to the future, I would like to work as a Junior Software Developer to gain more skills and experience and be supported by leading professionals.

SKILLS

- Web Technology: HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript, GitHub. Flask.
- Core Programming Languages: Python, SQL, MongoDB & JavaScript

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

- Memory Game: Used JavaScript to customise a basic memory game: added another level and a timer.
- Film's Database: Used Python SQLite library to create a web application that allows the user to add, edit, delete, and generate reports based on release year, rating, or genre from a film's database.
- Songs' Database: Used Python SQLite library and Flask to create a web application that allows the user to add, edit, delete, and update songs on the database.
- Student Performance in Exams: I did data exploration, trained three models to predict the total score. I evaluated the models, and chose the best performing one. I then communicated the results by plotting horizontal bar charts to show feature importance of each feature.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SUPPLY TEACHER January 2022 - Present

DIFFERENT SCHOOLS

- Collaborating with Lead Teachers, Assistant Teachers, and School Administrators to make sure students are safe.
- Promoting in-class engagement and good behaviour.
- Following lesson plans from permanent teachers.

TRAINEE DATA ANALYST July 2022 – October 2022

HI-TECH PLUS (WWW.HI-TECHPLUS.CO.UK)

- Interpreted data, analysed the result, and created analytical report
- Created rich interactive visualizations through data interpretation and analysis (Google Data Studio, PowerBI)
- Provided technical expertise on data cleaning, data mining, and web scrapping.
- Created database connections, schema, and developed gueries using SQL commands.
- Developed programming scripts, plots, and analyse data using Python.
- Assisted senior data analyst as needed.

DEVELOPER June 2022 – July 2022

STOCKHUB - CONTRACT

- Working on the investment platform
- Web scraping to find investment data
- Design the site's responsiveness to various devices.

MATH & SCIENCE TEACHER (SESSIONAL TEACHER)

October 2020 - March 2022

LEARNINGSURE COLLEGE

- Planned and delivered the lessons to students of mixed abilities.
- Created quizzes to assess students' progress and inform future planning.

ENGLISH TEACHER September 2019 – May 2020

QUALITY EDUCATION COMPANY, KSA

- Introduced Google Sheets to enable teachers to collaborate in various admin work including submitting students' results, students' performance data, and a list of students' profiles and reports.
- Used formulas and other Excel tools to analyse students' results from quizzes that were conducted thrice in a term to help teachers with planning for ongoing class activities.

ENGLISH, MATH INSTRUCTOR & COORDINATOR

September 2012 - May 2019

LAUREATE VOCATIONAL SA, KSA

- This was a vocational college for students who did not make it to the university.
- Planned, and delivered the lessons to students of mixed abilities.
- Created quizzes to assess student's progress and inform future planning.

- Introduced Google Sheets to enable teachers to collaborate in various admin work including submitting students' results, students' performance data, and a list of students' profiles and reports.
- Used formulas and other Excel tools to analyse students' results from quizzes that were conducted thrice in a term to help teachers with planning for ongoing class activities.
- Created an LMS and administered it using shared folders and files: schedules, grade sheets, meeting minutes and resource sharing, and creation of a COP.
- Utilized MOODLE for summative and formative assessments.
- Provided IT Support to the teachers and helped install the software in the college labs whenever the IT Support staff was busy occupied or absent.

MATH TEACHER September 2010 – June 2012

AL-ROWAD INTERNATIONAL SCHOOLS, KSA

EDUCATION

APPLIED DATA SCIENCE LAB March 2022 – Present

WORLD QUANT UNIVERSITY

• Completed a series of end-to-end data science projects, queried different types of databases, cleaned messy data and built predictive models for regression and classification.

• Created compelling visualisations to present prediction results.

DIGITAL SKILLS BOOTCAMP: SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

March 2022 – June 2022

JUST IT TRAINING LTD, LONDON

• A twelve-week intensive boot camp covering the fundamentals of Web and Software development.

APPLIED DATA SCIENCE II: MACHINE LEARNING & STATISTICAL ANALYSIS

September 2021 – December 2021

WORLD QUANT UNIVERSITY

APPLIED DATA SCIENCE I: SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING & PYTHON

April 2021 – June 2021

WORLD QUANT UNIVERSITY

PROFESSIONAL GRADUATE CERTIFICATE OF EDUCATION (SECONDARY MATHEMATICS)

September 2007 – June 2009

October 2001 - June 2005

UNIVERSITY OF EAST LONDON

MENG IN CHEMICAL ENGINEERING (2:1)

IMPERIAL COLLEGE LONDON

• Core Modules: Mathematics, Process Analysis

• Languages: Maple Programming Language

REFERENCES

Available upon request